[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
Welcome to session 206,
欢迎来到 206 号会议
Introducing Password Autofill
“Introducing 密码自动填充 for App
for Apps.
（App 中的密码自动填充）”
My name is Ricky Mondello.
我是 Ricky Mondello
And I am thrilled to be able to
我非常高兴能
tell you about Password
为大家讲解
Autofill, a new feature in iOS
iOS 11 的全新功能 密码自动填充
11 that puts passwords that your
它能够把你的用户
users have already saved in
存储在 Safari 和
Safari and in iCloud Keychain
iCloud 钥匙串中的密码
directly on the keyboard within
直接填写到你的 App
your apps to make logging in
内部的键盘中
super simple.
让登录变的超简单
We made Password Autofill
我们设计密码自动填充
because logging into apps is
是因为在 App 中登录
hard.
非常麻烦
It's a source of friction.
这很让人头疼
Personally, when I've downloaded
就我个人而言
a new app from the Store and
如果我从 App Store 里下载了一个新 App
I've seen the login screen,
看到登录页面
sometimes I've just switched
有时候我就会
back to Safari where I knew I
回到 Safari 上面
was already logged into the
因为我知道我已经在这个 App 的网站上
app's website.
登录过
But beyond an inconvenience for
除了这种不方便
me, for so many people any
很多人还经历过
experience dealing with
处理密码相关的问题
passwords is a source of real
而带来的挫败感甚至是
frustration or even panic.
恐慌
So the truth is, although having
实际情况是
to log into your apps is really
尽管在 App 上登录是非常重要的
important, it is a source of
但它所造成的不便和困扰
friction that can lead to users
会让用户选择
abandoning your app.
放弃这个 App
And none of us want that to
我们可不想看到
happen.
这种情况
You make awesome apps.
你做出了这么好的 App
We want users to use them.
我们想让用户使用它们
Fortunately, in iOS 11 Password
幸好 在 iOS 11 里的
Autofill can help.
密码自动填充可以解决这个问题
Let me explain.
我来解释一下
iOS and MacOS have a password
iOS 和 macOS
manager that's built in,
有一个内置的密码管理系统
integrated into Safari.
集成在 Safari 上面
And you've probably seen it
你们可能
before.
之前见过
When you're logging into a
你登录一个网站的时候
website, it offers to save your
它就会问你要不要存储
passwords.
密码
And the next time that you come
下次你回到
back to that website, it fills
这个网站上
them automatically for you to
它就会自动替你填充密码
make logging in really easy.
让登录变的非常简单
And I want you to know that
我希望你们知道
Safari takes the security of
Safari 把用户密码的
users' passwords extremely
安全性看得极其
seriously.
重要
If the user has saved a password
如果用户在你的网站上
for your website, Safari will
存储了一个密码
only ever fill that password on
Safari 就只在你的网站上
your website.
填充这个密码
Passwords for your website won't
你网站的密码绝不会
be offered on any other
被泄露在其他
websites.
网站上
And of course, if the user wants
当然 如果用户希望
to look up one of their
在设备上查找某个密码
passwords on a device, viewing
那就需要认证
the passwords requires them to
才能查看
authenticate, either with Touch
使用 Touch ID 或者
ID or with their passcode.
或者使用密码
The point is, iOS keeps these
总而言之 iOS 能保证
passwords secure on device.
这些密码在设备上的安全
And of course, iOS synchs all of
当然 iOS 会用 iCloud 钥匙串
these passwords across a user's
在同一用户的所有设备上
devices using iCloud Keychain.
同步这些密码
And this makes it super easy to
这会让不同设备登录
log in across multiple devices.
变得超级简单
And this, too, is secure.
同样也是安全的
We actually have a really
实际上
approachable white paper on
我们在 Apple.com 上
Apple.com that describes the
有一个白皮书
security model of iCloud
描述了 iCloud 钥匙串的
Keychain.
安全模型
And it goes into a great amount
上面非常详细地
of detail about how and why
讲述了 Apple 在看不到
Apple cannot see a user's
用户同步密码的情况下
synched passwords, but it still
是如何让它们仍然
makes them available on all the
可以出现在
devices.
不同设备上
Safari AutoFill and iCloud
Safari 的自动填充与 iCloud 钥匙串
Keychain are built directly into
直接内置在
iOS and MacOS.
iOS 和 macOS 里面
Safari AutoFill is enabled by
Safari 自动填充对所有用户
default for all users.
都是默认开启的
And every user is prompted to
每一个用户在
turn on iCloud Keychain when
设置新设备时都会被询问
they set up a new device.
是否要使用 iCloud 钥匙串
These features are extremely
这些功能是非常
popular.
受欢迎的
Lots of your users have
很多用户都把
passwords saved in iCloud
密码存储在
Keychain and Safari AutoFill.
iCloud 钥匙串和 Safari 自动填充里
And what iOS 11 does is it takes
iOS 11 的不同之处在于
these passwords that already
让这些已经存储在钥匙串里的
saved in the Keychain and makes
密码也能被用于
them available on the keyboard
你 App 内的
within your apps.
键盘上
And I think the best way to
我想了解这个功能的
understand this is to see it.
最好方式就是眼见为实
So let's start off with a demo.
我们一起看一个演示
So, what I have right here is
这里展示的是 Shiny
Shiny, which is a demo app.
这是一个演示 App
And it's personally my favorite
这是我个人最喜欢的
demo app for logging in and
用于登录演示的 App
seeing a picture of something
在它上面
that's pleasant every single
每天都可以看到
day.
一幅美妙的图片
So I'm going to open up this
我现在要打开
app.
这个 App
And it has a very standard login
这是一个很标准的
screen, like many of your apps
登录页面 和你们的很多 App 一样
do, with a username and a
有用户名栏
password field.
和密码栏
So like any user would, I'm
像每一个用户一样
going to tap into the username
我会点按
field.
用户名栏
And one of the first things
你首先注意到的
you'll probably notice is that
可能就是在键盘上方
directly above the keyboard
这里有一个
there's the QuickType bar.
QuickType 栏
And the QuickType bar is
这个 QuickType 栏
offering my password from the
就为我提供了 Shiny 网站
website for Shiny.
上面的密码
And with one tap, that
只需点按一下
information is filled.
就自动填上了
And with another tap, I'm logged
再点一下
in.
就登录成功了
That's an adorable puppy, 13 out
这小狗真可爱 如果满分 10 分的话
of 10.
我要给 13 分
So let's do that one more time.
再来一遍
It went by pretty quickly.
这很快就完成了
This time I'll just happen to
这次我碰巧点到了
touch into the password field.
密码栏
And I'm offered the same thing.
效果是一样的
I can tap and tap.
点一下 再点一下
And I'm logged in.
登录成功
Another good dog.
又有一条乖狗狗出现了
So one thing I want to point out
在展示的时候
while I'm showing you this is I
我还想指出一点
mentioned a moment ago that iOS
就是刚才提到的
takes password security very
iOS 极其重视密码的
seriously.
安全性
And so the big thing to notice
所以要注意
here is iOS isn't guessing that
iOS 不是去猜测
shiny.example.com is the website
shiny.example.com
for the Shiny app.
是 Shiny 这个 App 的官网
There is a strong two-way secure
在这个 App 和这个网站之间
association between that app and
有一个安全的强双向联系
that website that allows iOS to
让 iOS 能够
put the exact right credential
使用户需要的
that the user's looking for
那个用户名和密码
right on the QuickType bar.
出现在 QuickType 栏里
All right.
好
Let's go back to some slides.
咱们往回看一下
You just saw that iOS 11 put the
大家刚才看到 iOS 11
password that I needed to log
把我登录 Shiny 所需的密码
into Shiny directly on the
直接填在了
QuickType bar above the
键盘上方的 QuickType 栏里
keyboard, which made logging in
这让登录变的简单
as simple as two taps.
只需点按两下
Now, I have no reason to abandon
现在 我再也不需要
the app and go back to Safari
离开 App 回到 Safari
where I was already logged in.
就是刚才已经登录过的网页了
It's just as easy to log into
登录到 App 上面
the app.
就这么简单
Quick show of hands.
快速举手回答
How many of you have a screen in
多少人的 App 里
your app that looks like this
有这样的页面
one with a username and a
需要输入用户名
password field?
和密码的
All right.
好的
That's a lot of you.
看来人数不少
And you're all in the right
你们都
place.
来对地方了
So, one more show of hands.
请再举一下手
How many of those apps are you
在这些 App 中 有多少是
logging into your own backend
登录到你自己的后端
that you manage yourself instead
而不是到一个
of a third party service?
第三方服务平台上面的
All right.
好
That's a lot of you.
人数也不少
For everyone who kept their hand
对于那些
up, who raised it a second time,
举了两次手的人来说
I'm going to be talking to you
我这个演讲的
throughout most of this
大部分内容都是
presentation.
为你们准备的
But if you're logging into a
如果你登录到
third party service like a
第三方服务平台 比如
social network, I'll have a
社交网络
little something for you toward
那么我在这场演讲的最后
the end.
准备了一些内容给你们
We want Password AutoFill to
我们希望密码自动填充
work for as many of your apps as
能够应用到
possible.
尽可能多的 App 上
So we built heuristics into iOS
我们在 iOS 里内置了启发式算法
that make some parts of Password
这会让密码自动填充
AutoFill work automatically in
的一些工作
many apps without you
在很多 App 上面自动进行
necessarily having to change
无须你改动
anything.
任何东西
However, for your users to get
然而 要是想让用户
the best experience where the
得到最佳体验
exact right credential shows up
让最正确的个人认证信息
on the QuickType bar, we're
出现在 QuickType 栏
going to need a little bit of
我们还需要你们的
your help.
一点帮助
So what we're going to focus on
本次会议接下来的时间
for the rest of this session is
我们要集中讲解一下
guaranteeing that your apps get
如何保证你们的 App
the experience that you just saw
也能获得刚才在 Shiny 上看到的
in the Shiny app.
一样的效果
And we'll do that by walking
要做到这一点
through these topics.
我们来看这些主题
The first topic is about making
第一个主题讲的是
the QuickType bar appear in your
如何让 QuickType 栏
username and password fields in
出现在你的 App 的
your app.
用户名和密码栏内
The second is about making sure
第二个主题讲的是
that the passwords are filled
如何保证在 App 中
properly into the app.
合适的位置填入密码
And that your app works properly
并让你的 App 在用户
after a user taps on one of the
点按一个选项后
suggestions.
正常运行起来
Then, we'll talk about making
然后 我们会讲到如何
sure that the exact right
保证你的用户需要的
credential that your user is
个人用户名和密码信息
looking for, the credential from
也就是你网站上的信息
your website, shows up on the
会准确地出现在
left-hand side of the QuickType
QuickType 栏的
bar.
左手边
And then at the end, we'll
最后我们会回来
circle back around and talk
再说一说
about authenticating against a
对第三方服务的认证
third party service, a service
也就是区别于你的 App
that's not the same as your app.
的服务
So let's get started by talking
咱们先来讲一讲
about making the QuickType bar
如何让 QuickType 栏
appear.
出现
The first thing to know about
首先要知道
the QuickType bar appearing is
关于让 QuickType 栏出现的情况
that it will only appear if you
只有在你的 iOS 设备上
have at least one saved password
至少有一个存储的密码的情况下
on an iOS device.
QuickType 栏才会出现
There's no need for us to offer
如果根本没有密码
Password AutoFill if there are
我们当然也就不需要
no passwords to fill.
密码自动填充了
The next thing to know is that
第二件事
UITextView and UITextField are
UITextView 和 UITextField
automatically eligible for
是自动为
consideration or Password
Password 自动填充
AutoFill.
准备的
So, if you're using these
所以 如果你们已经在 UIKit 里
standard controls out of UIKit,
用到这些标准控制
you're already in a really good
那就已经有一个很好的
place.
开始了
However, if you're rolling your
如果你是使用
own text fields, no need to
自己的文本栏
worry.
那也不用担心
If your text field conforms to
如果你的文本栏符合
UITextInput, it's also eligible
UITextInput 那么它
for Password Autofill.
也适用于密码自动填充
And I mentioned this earlier,
我之前提到过这一点
but iOS is going to use
iOS 会使用
heuristics to determine where to
启发式算法来决定
show the QuickType bar in your
在你的用户名和密码
username and your password
栏中启动
fields.
QuickType 栏
And iOS's heuristics are pretty
iOS 的启发式算法
good.
非常棒
But what we're here to do is to
但我们要做的是
guarantee that your app has
保证你的 App 具有
Password AutoFill.
密码自动填充功能
And we can guarantee that by
我们能够保证
having you tell iOS which of
能让你告诉 iOS
your fields is the username
哪里是用户名栏
field and which is the password
哪里是
field.
密码栏
And the way that we'll do this
我们实现的方法
is through UITextContentType.
就是通过 UITextContentType
By setting a content type on the
在文本栏中设置一个
text fields.
内容类型
UITextContentType was introduced
在 iOS 10 中 UITextContentType 是被作为
as an optional property on the
UITextInputTraits 协议的
UITextInputTraits protocol in
一项可选属性
iOS 10.
出现的
iOS uses it to have a better
iOS 能用它
understanding of what
更好地理解
information is in your text
你的文本栏中的
fields.
信息
So you could imagine that iOS
你可以想象 iOS
would offer a different and
能够提供一个不同的
better keyboard or auto
且更好的键盘
corrections if it knew that your
或者自动更正功能 就像它知道
users was typing an email
用户是在输入
address versus, say, their last
邮件地址还是
name.
他们的名字一样
Here are the text content types
这里是 iOS 10 提供的
that are present in iOS 10, just
文本内容类型
to give you a refresher.
大家都见过
And as you've probably guessed,
你们可能都猜到了
in iOS 11 there are two new text
在 iOS 11 中有两个新的
content types, username and
文本内容类型 也就是用户名和
password, that you can tag your
密码 你可以把它们
fields with.
标记在你的栏上
So to guarantee that Password
为了保证密码自动填充
AutoFill is working in your
在你的 App 中顺利工作
apps, we're going to deploy
我们需要用到
UITextContentType.
UITextContentType
That's going to be our guarantee
这就是我们用来保证
that Password AutoFill is
密码自动填充在 App 里
available in your app.
能够顺利工作的利器
You can set text content types
你可以在代码内部
from within code.
设置文本内容类型
Or, with an interface filter.
或者使用接口构建器
And we'll show you how to do
我们等一下就会展示
that in a little bit.
怎么做到这一点
The username text content type
如果你的 App
is particularly useful if your
提供了双屏登录体验
app has a two-screen login
也就是用户名栏和密码栏
experience where your username
在不同的屏或视图上
field is on a different view or
用户名文本内容类型
screen than your password.
会特别有用
In this case, if you tag your
在这种情况下 如果你
username field with the username
把用户名文本内容类型
text content type, we'll be able
标记在用户名栏
to offer the QuickType bar on
我们就能为双屏提供
both of the screens.
QuickType 栏了
If you're already using the
如果你已经在用
email address text content type,
电子邮件地址的文本内容类型
there's no need to worry.
也不用担心
You can combine the username
你可以把用户名
text content type and the email
文本内容类型和电子邮件键盘
keyboard to give your users the
结合起来 让你的用户
best of both worlds, where they
在两种情形下都能获得更好体验
get an email address keyboard
既能获取电子邮件地址键盘
and QuickType Autofill.
也能体验 QuickType 自动填充
The password text content type
密码文本内容类型
is particularly useful if you
如果你的 App 里
have a feature in your app that
有直接用文本显示
reveals the password that the
用户正在输入的密码
user is typing in plain text to
这样为他们提供便利
help them out.
的功能 这会非常有用
When your field is in plain text
如果你的栏是以文本形式出现
iOS won't be able to tell that
iOS 就不能分辨它是
it's a password field unless you
密码栏 除非你把这个栏
tag the field as a password.
定义成密码
So if you do that, the QuickType
如果你这样做了
bar will still work in that
QuickType 栏中这个栏仍然有效
field, even when it's not a
即便它并不是一个
secure entry.
安全的条目
And at this point, once you've
到这一步 你这样做以后
done this, you might see a
就会看到一个
Password AutoFill QuickType bar
密码自动填充 QuickType 栏
in your app with its key icon on
在你的 App 里 钥匙图标
the right, but without any
在右边 但是在左边
specific credentials showing up
没有任何特定的内容
on the left.
出现
This is actually expected.
这是必要的一步
And it's a really good first
是个良好的
step.
开端
In a little bit we'll talk about
很快我们就会讲到
making your website's passwords
如何让你网站的密码
show up on the left.
出现在左边
But what seeing this bar means
看到这个栏就意味着
is that iOS is ready to offer
iOS 已经准备好提供
Password AutoFill.
密码自动填充了
And if users tap on that key on
如果用户点按了
the right-hand side, they'll be
右手边的钥匙图标
able to authenticate using Touch
他们就能够使用 Touch ID
ID and see a list of their
进行认证 并看到一系列
passwords that they can search
密码 他们可以从中
through or scroll through in
寻找 滚动
order to fill one of those
并找到合适的密码
passwords within your app.
填入你的 App
And once they've found the right
当他们找到了合适的密码
password, and they tap it, iOS
点按一下
will fill that information into
iOS 就能把这个密码填入
your fields.
你的栏
Which brings us to our next
这就让我们进入了
topic, which is ensuring the
下一主题
information that's filled into
也就是让你的 App 能理解
your text fields is understood
填入的文本栏的信息
by your app and that users able
并让用户
to log in successfully
在这之后
afterward.
能够成功登录
iOS is going to do its best to
iOS 会尽力
put information into your
把信息按照
username and password fields in
用户自己填写的那种方式
a very similar way to how users
填入到你的用户名栏
would type that information
和密码栏
themselves.
之中
But it's still a good idea to
但还是有必要测试
test that your app behaves
以保证你的 App
properly after information has
在信息被自动填写后
been autofilled.
能够正常工作
What we want to see is that
我们希望看到
users are able to just tap your
用户只需轻点
sign-in button and log directly
登录按钮 然后就直接
in.
登录了
So let's talk about what you
下面我们讲一下
need to know about how Password
密码自动填充
AutoFill fills into your app.
是如何进入你的 App 的
The first thing is something
第一件事大家可能
you've already seen, which is
已经知道了 那就是
that iOS will fill both the
iOS 会通过一个动作
username and the password fields
填写用户名
in a single gesture.
和密码栏
iOS will change your app's first
iOS 会通过更改你的 App 的
responder in order to do this.
第一响应对象做到这一点
iOS is going to do this even if
即便你的 App 会
your app prevents changing the
阻止更改第一响应对象
first responder at that time.
iOS 也会这样做
So if you're doing something
所以如果你的 App
like this, it's worth knowing.
是这样的话 希望你能有所了解
A moment ago I showed you the
刚才我向大家展示了
flow where a user taps on the
用户点按钥匙图标
key icon and Touch ID comes up.
Touch ID 出现的情形
And when Touch ID appears, your
Touch ID 出现后
app will become inactive.
你的 App 就不活动了
And that's worth knowing because
需要了解这一点
it leads directly into our first
因为这会直接导致
best practice.
下面的情况
Which is that when Touch ID
也就是 Touch ID
appears, there's no need for you
出现时 你不需要
to tear down your login UI or
在 App 不活跃的时候
hide it when your app becomes
把登录 UI 拽下去或者把它
inactive.
隐藏起来
Because if you do this, all a
因为如果你这样做了
user is going to see is tapping
用户就会看到
on the key, finding the right
点按钥匙图标
password and tapping it.
找到合适的密码并点按
And then iOS isn't going to be
然后 iOS 却不能自动填写
able to fill anything because
任何内容
the text fields will have
因为文本栏
disappeared.
不见了
So, it might be a good idea to
所以 应该
hide sensitive information in
在你的 App 不活跃时
your app when your app becomes
隐藏敏感
inactive.
信息
But if a user actually hasn't
但如果一个用户没有完成
finished logging in yet, that's
登录的话 那么这就
probably not necessary.
没有什么必要了
You might have buttons in your
可能在你的 App 上有
app, like a login button or a
按键 比如登录键
sign-in button, that only lights
或是注册键
up and enables itself once
只在有信息
there's actually information
被填入用户名
filled into the username and
和密码栏时才会亮起
password field.
并且生效
And the best practice here is to
这里最好的方法
us did change notifications or
是使用“did change”通知
delegate methods to revalidate
或者委托方法让这些按键
those buttons whenever the text
在文本发生变化时重新生效
If you're using UITextField,
如果你正在使用 UITextField
there's a notification that you
那么有一个通知可以
can use.
派上用场
If you're using UITextView,
如果你正在使用 UITextView
there's a notification and a
那么有一个通知和一个
delegate method.
委托方法可以用
And if you're rolling your own
如果你在使用你自己的
custom text input, if you can
定制文本输入 如果你能够
form the UITextInputDelegate,
完成 UITextInputDelegate
there's a delegate method that
那么有一个委托方法
you can listen to again to
可以为你所用
revalidate your buttons.
让按键重新生效
And when you're doing that
你在做这些确认的时候
validation, you should read
应该直接从
information directly from your
文本栏的文字属性中
text field's text property.
读取信息
UIKit makes it incredibly cheap
UIKit 让从文本栏中
to read information out of a
读取信息变得
text field.
轻而易举
And it's always accurate.
而且总是很准确
If you do this, you'll eliminate
如果你这样做了
categorically an entire class of
你就会避免
bugs that you can have with
很多 Bug 这些 Bug 在使用
cash-in validation based on what
基于输入文本栏的
information is entered into your
cash-in 验证时
text fields.
可能会出现
And that's it.
这就好了
That's just a few best practices
这些方法是为了
for ensuring that after a user
保证用户在使用自动填充之后
has used AutoFill, that your app
能够在你的 App 上
is able to login successfully.
成功登录
And users can go about their
然后用户就可以
business.
继续使用了
Which brings us to our third
接下来就要谈到第三个主题
topic, which is making sure that
也就是要保证
the QuickType bar is showing the
QuickType 栏会填入
exact right credentials for your
你的网站的正确的认证信息
website.
在测试的这一步
you might still have what we saw
出现的可能还是我们之前见到的
earlier, which is a bar with a
也就是一个带有钥匙图标的栏
key on it, but without any
但在左边没有任何
specific credentials on the
特定的身份认证
left.
信息
But as you know, in order to
但我们知道 为了要给用户
give users the best experience,
最佳的体验
the one that is most going to
就一定要尽量避免
reduce the odds that they
他们卸载你的 App
abandon your app, we'll want the
这个可能性
exact correct credentials
因此我们需要 QuickType 栏
showing up on the QuickType bar.
一定要显示正确的身份信息
And I touched on this briefly
我在刚才的演示中
during the demo earlier, but
稍微提过这一点
Password AutoFill will only put
密码自动填充只会在
credentials on the QuickType bar
安全的情况下才会把身份信息
when it is safe to do so.
显示在 QuickType 栏上
When it's secure.
只有安全的时候才行
iOS is not guessing what
iOS 不会去猜是哪一个
websites are affiliated with
网站跟你的 App 有关
your app to find out which
然后去找哪一个是
passwords are correct for your
对应你的 App的正确
app.
密码
iOS knows.
iOS 本来就知道
So if you've adopted universal
如果你采用了通用链接
links, that feature that can
这个特性能够
open up links when a user taps
让用户在你的 App 内
on them inside of your app,
点按链接时把它们打开
rather than opening them up in
而不是在 Safari 内打开
Safari, if you've done that, you
如果你做到了这一点
might actually already see that
那么你可能已经发现了
iOS understands that your app
iOS 知道你的 App
and your website are associated.
和你的网站是关联的
And it'll put the right
然后它将能在 QuickType 栏中
credentials on the QuickType
输入正确信息了
But if you haven't adopted
但如果你没有使用
universal links, or it doesn't
通用链接 或者
really make sense for you to do
你认为这样做没有意义
so, there's no need to worry.
也不用担心
We have a dedicated technology
我们有一个很棒的技巧
to linking your app and your
能够让你的 App 和网站
website together strongly.
建立强力联系
And I'm going to walk you
我现在就带大家
through it.
看看怎么做
In this diagram it's your app on
这个图标中 左边是
the left.
你的 App
And on the right is your web
右边是你的网站服务器
server or your backend.
或者你的后端
So the ideas is that your app,
我们的目标是让你的 App
through its signed entitlements,
通过签名认证
says what website or websites it
指出哪个或哪些网站
is affiliated with.
和它有关
And whenever your app is
只要用户安装了这个 App
installed or iOS installs an
或者 iOS 安装了这个 App 的更新
update, iOS is going to check
iOS 就会去
with that domain at a particular
通过一个特定的文件路径
file path to see, to look for
检查那个栏的名称
some information.
查找某些信息
If you don't know the well-known
如果你不熟悉这个“.well-known”目录
directory, it's just a standard
没关系 其实它就是一个
place to put files for
储存文件挖掘信息的地方
information discovery, like the
就像我接下来
file I'm about to tell you
要介绍给你们的这个
about:
文件
Apple-app-site-association.
apple-app-site-association
iOS will only ever attempt to
iOS 只会通过 HTTPS
fetch this file over HTTPS, over
这个安全链接
a secure connection.
来试图获取这个文件
In response to that request,
作为这个请求的回应
your website can return a JSON
你的网站可以发回一个 JSON
response.
响应
And if that JSON response is
如果这个 JSON 响应
formatted properly, what it can
格式正确 它就会说
say is: Here is the list of apps
这里是与我有关的
that I'm associated with.
App 的列表
And if the app points to the
如果这个 App 指向这个网站
website, and the website points
而这个网站也
right back to the app, boom!
指向这个 App
We have a secure two-way link.
我们就有了一个安全的双向链接
So to put what I've told you
为了把我给大家讲的东西
about so far into practice,
付诸实践
particularly with establishing
特别是要做你的 App
this secure connection between
和你的网站之间
your app and your website, I am
建立安全的联系
delighted to invite my colleague
我将请我的同事
Maureen Daum to the stage to
Maureen Daum 上台
give you a demo.
为大家做演示
Maureen.
Maureen
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Ricky.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Ricky
So, here I have the Shiny app
现在我有 Shiny 这个 App
before we've done any work to
我们还没有在上面使用
make Password AutoFill work with
密码自动
it.
填充
So when I tap in the username
当我点按用户名
field, iOS automatically
栏时 iOS 就自动
detected that this is in fact
检测到这是
the username field.
用户名栏
And it gives us the Password
然后它就会自然地给我们
AutoFill QuickType bar -- thank
密码自动填充 QuickType 栏
you -- for free.
谢谢
So now users, if they don't
那么现在 用户们
remember their credentials, can
如果不记得自己的身份信息了
tap on the Key icon,
他们就可以点按钥匙图标
authenticate with Touch ID and
使用 Touch ID 进行认证
find the right credential.
查找正确的身份信息
So here it is.
找到了
So this is a great experience
这对那些记不清
for my users that might not
自己身份信息的用户来说
remember their credentials.
是很棒的体验
But what I really want to make
但我很想让他们
it even easier for them to log
登录的过程变得更简单
in is to have those credentials
让他们的身份信息
show up right on the QuickType
直接显示在 QuickType
bar.
栏上
So I'm going to do two things in
我在这个演示中要做
this demo.
两件事
The first is to guarantee that
第一件事是要保证
we get this password QuickType
我们能得到这个密码 QuickType 栏
bar instead of just relying on
而不是只能依靠
the heuristics.
启发式算法
And the second thing is to get
第二件事是要保证
the right credentials on the
QuickType 栏上的身份信息
QuickType bar.
是正确的
So let's do that first step,
我们先来做第一步
guaranteeing that we get the
保证我们能够得到
credentials.
身份信息
To do this, I'm going to tag my
要做到这一点
username and password fields
我要把用户名和密码栏
with the right content type.
与正确的内容类型联系起来
So here's my username field.
这里是用户名
And I've already set its content
我已经把内容类型
type to email address, because
设定为电子邮件地址
some of my usernames might be
因为一些用户名就是
email addresses.
电子邮件地址
But if I switch this to
但如果我把这个换成
username, down here at the
用户名 就在最下面
bottom, I can set the keyboard
我可以把键盘类型
type to email address.
设定成“Email Address（电子邮件地址）”
So go down here the keyboard
在这里找到键盘类型
type and set that one to email.
然后把它设成电子邮件
So now if the user has to type
现在如果用户
in their username, they'll still
输入用户名 他们仍然会
get the right keyboard.
获取正确的键盘
And now I'll go to password and
现在我要去把密码
set that content type to
的内容类型设定成
password, all the way at the
“Password（密码）” 就在最
bottom.
下面
So, I'm going to rerun this just
我再次运行一遍
to verify that we still get the
以证实我们仍然可以让
QuickType bar showing up.
QuickType 栏出现
We don't expect anything to have
我们不指望有任何变化
changed because iOS was already
因为 iOS 已经
detecting it.
检测到了
But it's good to make sure.
但确认一下也好
So now, once the login screen
现在 登录页面出现之后
comes up, we can tap in and we
我们可以点进去
still get the QuickType bar,
仍然会有 QuickType 栏
which is great.
这很棒
So now, to get the credentials
现在要让身份信息出现
showing up, we need to tell iOS
我们需要告诉 iOS
that our app and our website are
我们的 App 和网站是
associated.
关联的
And to do this, we'll adopt the
要做到这一点 我们要用到
web credentials associated
网络认证关联
domain service.
域名服务
So, to do this, the first step,
要做到这一点 首先
is to make our app tell iOS what
要让我们的 App 告诉 iOS
websites it's associated with.
哪些网站与它关联
So we'll go here to the
我们来到
Capabilities tab in our app and
App 里的“Capabilities（能力）”标签页
turn on Associated Domains.
打开“Associated Domains（关联域名）”
So now I have the ability to add
现在我就能添加
domains that my app is
与我的 App 关联的
associated with.
域名了
So click the Plus button and
点按加号
Xcode as a placeholder domain
Xcode 给出一个占位
for me.
域名
So it has the web credentials
它有“webcredentials”的前缀
:prefix, because we're using the
因为我们正在使用
web credential service.
网站认证服务
And then you will replace
然后你可以把
example.com with the domain your
example.com 替换成你的 App
app is associated with.
关联的域名
So my app is associated with
我的 App 关联的域名是
Shiny.example.com.
Shiny.example.com
And when you add a domain, Xcode
你添加一个域名时
will do two things.
Xcode 会做两件事
The first is it adds an
首先是在你的 Entitlement 文件中
entitlement to your entitlements
添加一个 Entitlement
file so that when your app is
这样在你的 App 被安装后
installed iOS will look at this
iOS 就会查看这一系列域名
list of domains and go to each
进入每一个域名
one of them to find the
去查找
Apple-App-Site-Association file.
apple-app-site-association 文件
The second thing it does is it
它做的第二件事是
makes sure that your app has
确保你的 App 的
associated domains enabled.
关联域名是打开的
So if your app ID does not have
如果你的 App ID 没有
this enabled, you won't see a
打开这个
checkmark next to this second
你在这第二条旁边就看不到
thing.
对勾
It will have an error.
而是会有一个叉
So, if you see an error there,
如果你看到了一个叉
it's really easy to fix.
也很容易改正
You just need to go to the
你只需要进入
Developer Portal, select your
Developer Portal 选择你的
app ID, and turn on Associated
App ID 然后打开 Associated
Domains.
Domains
And then it will be fixed.
然后就搞定了
So that is all we had to do to
我们做到这些
tell iOS that our app is
就能够告诉 iOS 我们的 App
associated with our website.
与我们的网站的关联了
But now we need to make our
现在我们需要获得网站
website agree and point back to
的同意 然后指回我们的 App
our app so that iOS can
这样 iOS 就能够建立
establish the two-way link.
双向链接了
So to do this, I'll create an
要做到这一点 我要建立一个
Apple App Site association file.
apple-app-site-association 文件
So, here's some JSON that
这里的 JSON
specifies we're using the web
指明我们正在使用
credential service, which
认证服务
matches what we saw in Xcode.
这与我们在 Xcode 中见到的相符
Then within this dictionary is a
在这个字典里面
list of all the app IDs of the
是我们的网站关联的
apps our website is associated
所有 App 的
with.
App ID 列表
And my website only knows about
我的网站就只与 Shiny 这一个 App
the Shiny app.
相关联
So its app ID consists of the
所以它的 App ID 包括
Team Identifier, which you can
团队标识符 你可以在
find on the Developer Portal,
Developer Portal 里找到它
followed by a period, and then
后面是一个英文句号 再后面是你的
your bundle identifier.
数据包标识符
So let's save that.
我们把它存储一下
And now I need to get it onto my
现在要把它放在我的
server.
服务器上
And this step might look
这一步对每个人来说
different for you depending on
可能略有不同 取决于
how your website is set up.
你们各自网站的设置
But I'm just going to use SCP to
我要用 SCP 把它
copy it up there, to the
复制到这里
.well-known subdirectory.
到 well-known 子目录里
Great. So it's up there.
好了 出现了
And then just to double check,
为了保证生效
I'm going to go into Safari and
我要去 Safari 里
visit the site that iOS is going
访问这个 iOS 即将要
to look at.
查看的网站
So it's HTTPS
网址是
Shiny.example.com/.well-known/
https://shiny.example.com/.well-known/
apple-app-site-association.
apple-app-site-association/
And when I go there, it's great.
进去后 很好
I see the JSON recreated.
看到 JSON 出现了
And I don't see any smart
没有看到智能引号
quotes, which could cause the
那会让 JSON
JSON to be malformed and
形式出错
therefore it wouldn't work.
那样就没有效果了
So, it looks like we're all set.
看上去我们没出什么问题
We've set up our app to point to
我们已经设置好 App 让它指向
our website.
我们的网站
Our website to point to our app.
网站也指向 App
So let's rerun this and see that
我们再运行一遍
we get the credentials we want
就会看到我们需要的身份信息
showing up on the QuickType bar.
出现在 QuickType 栏了
And when you're testing this on
你们的 App 测试时
your apps, make sure to test it
记住要在设备上测试
on a device, because Associated
因为 Associated Domains
Domains is a device-only
是设备独有
feature.
的功能
So here we are back in our app.
现在我们回到 App 上面
I tap in the username field.
我点按用户名栏
Great! We have the credentials
好的 我们需要的身份信息
right there on the QuickType
已经出现在 QuickType 栏
bar.
上面了
So my users can tap, fill them
用户可以点按 填入
in, one more tap, and then they
再次点按 然后他们
get to see a really adorable
就能看到这个可爱的小狗了
So that's how easy it is to
要保证密码自动填充
guarantee that Password AutoFill
在你的 App 上正常工作
will work in your app.
就这么简单
And that the credentials your
你的用户名需要的
users need will show up on the
身份信息会在 QuickType 栏中出现
QuickType bar to get them logged
让他们得以非常快速地
in really quickly.
登入网站
So now I'll hand it back over to
现在把时间交还给 Ricky
Ricky to tell you more.
继续为大家讲解
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Maureen.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Maureen
That was really cool.
这真的很酷
Maureen just showed you just how
Maureen 刚才为大家展示了
easy it is to set text content
在 Xcode 里设置文本内容类型
types from within Xcode.
是多么简单
She also showed you how to add
她还展示了
the web credentials associated
如何在 App 里的功能表中
domain capability in your app's
加入网络认证关联
Capabilities tab.
域名功能
And she told you that that
然后她还讲到这个功能
capability gets signed into your
是签入你 App 的
app's binary.
二进制文件里面的
And if you need to enable the
如果你们需要
associated domains feature on
在 Developer Portal 里面
the Developer Portal, it's
启用关联域名特性
really easy to find.
这很容易找到
I'll show you how to do it.
我来演示一下
First, you navigate to the
首先 进入
Developer Portal.
Developer Portal
And from there you can click on
然后你可以点按
Certificates, Identifiers and
“Certificates Identifiers &
Profiles, either in the side bar
Profiles” 侧边栏或者
or in the main content area.
主界面都可以
And from there you can select
然后你可以选择
App IDs and look at a list of
App ID 然后查看列表中的
app IDs that are associated with
与你的开发者账户关联的
your developer account.
App ID
And from there, if you select
然后 如果你选择了
the app ID that you'd like to
你想更改的 App ID
modify, you'll see a list of
你就会看到
services that can be enabled for
可以为你的 App 启动的
your app.
服务列表
And from there you can click the
然后你可以点按
Edit button and check the
“Edit”按钮 再把
Associated Domains checkbox.
“Associated Domains”复选框打勾
And that's it.
然后就完成了
You also saw just how easy it is
大家也看到了
to construct an
建立一个可以
Apple-App-Site-Association that
让网站指回 App 的
points back to your app from
apple-app-site-association
your website.
非常简单
It's just a few lines of JSON.
只需几行 JSON 就能完成
Maureen then uploaded that JSON
然后 Maureen 把这个 JSON 文件
file to be served from the
上传到了她的网络服务器根目录下的
.well-known standard directory
/.well-known/ 标准目录里面
You could also serve this file
你也可以把这个文件直接放在
from the root of the web server,
服务器的根目录下
but the well-known directory is
但我们推荐使用
preferred.
/.well-known/ 目录
And if this linkage doesn't work
如果在你第一次尝试的时候
the first time that you try it,
这一链接没有起作用
if you build and run your app
如果你构建并运行你的 App
and you're not seeing
却没有在 QuickType 栏中
credentials showing up on the
看到身份信息的话
QuickType bar, we have a few
我们有一些步骤
steps for you to help the bug.
帮助你解决这个 Bug
The SWCD daemon will log
SWCD Daemon 程序会在你
information about making
每一次运行你的 App
requests for setting up
并在设备上请求
associations between your app
在你的 App 和网站之间
and website on your device every
建立联系的时候
time that you build and run your
记录相关信息
So if something's not working,
所以如果出现问题的话
plug your device in, open up
插入你的设备
Console, and select the device
在侧边栏打开控制台
in the side bar and look for
选择设备 查找
logging from SWCD.
SWCD 的日志就可以了
On the slide right now you can
在幻灯片上
see what happens when I
你可以看到
accidentally put
我在 Xcode 里不小心把
wrong.example.com as my
wrong.example.com
associated domain inside of
当成了我的
Xcode.
关联域名
It wasn't able to find an
它找不到
Apple-App-Site-Association file.
apple-app-site-association 文件
But as soon as I corrected that
但只要我把域名修改成
to Shiny.example.com iOS was
shiny.example.com
able to find the
iOS 就能够找到
Apple-App-Site-Association file,
apple-app-site-association 文件了
verify the two-way link, and
验证双向链接
from there iOS can offer the
然后 iOS 就能够让
exact right credentials that
你的用户需要的
your users are looking for
正确的身份信息
directly on the QuickType bar.
直接出现在 QuickType 栏里了
And at this point you pretty
现在你已经差不多
much have all of the information
完全了解了
that you need to know to make
该如何让
Password AutoFill work really
密码自动填充顺利地
well in your app.
在你的 App 里工作
I'm hoping that this is one of
我希望这能够成为
the easiest to adopt features
你们想使用的功能里面
that you've ever wanted to
最容易掌握
adopt.
的一个
But before we wrap things up, I
但这结束之前
just want to quickly touch on a
我还想快速讲一下
few related topics to
关于认证和密码的
authentication and passwords,
一些主题
because since you're here,
既然大家来到这里
you're probably interested in
想必对这些主题也很感兴趣
And the first is about viewing,
第一是关于在 iOS 里
saving, and adding new passwords
查看 存储和添加
on iOS.
密码的问题
So besides Password AutoFill, we
除了密码自动填充
made another change related to
今年我们还做了另一个
iCloud Keychain this year.
与 iCloud 钥匙串相关的改进
And that was to move the list of
那就是把之前在设置里的
passwords that you could find in
密码列表向上
Settings up to a more prominent
迁移到了顶层
location at the top level called
一个更显眼的位置
Accounts and Passwords.
叫做 账户与密码
Inside of that section, users
在这个目录下面
will be able to authenticate
我们可以使用
with Touch ID, of course, to
Touch ID 进行认证
view a list of their safe
查看安全密码列表
passwords, and add new
还可以添加
passwords.
新密码
Now, after all of you have
在你们的 App 全部
adopted Password AutoFill in
采用了密码自动填充后
your apps, users aren't going to
用户也就没有理由
have a ton of reasons to come in
再到这里来
here to copy and paste passwords
拷贝粘贴
anymore.
密码了
But it can still be useful to
但它仍然是有用的
look up a password if you need
比如当你在朋友的设备上
to enter it on a friend's device
填写你的某个密码
where you don't have your iCloud
你没有 iCloud 钥匙串
Keychain.
就可以在这里查到
Okay, this whole time we've been
好了 我们一直在讲解
talking about a specific type of
一种特定形式的认证
authentication, where your app
也就是你的 App
and your website, they're the
和你的网站 它们的实体
same entity.
是同一个
You're logging into a service
你要登入你或者你的公司
that you or your company owns.
所拥有的一项服务
But I know that there's a
但我知道
different type of authentication
在座的一些人
that a bunch of you need, which
还需要另一种认证形式
is to log into a third party
也就是登入第三方服务
service like a popular social
比如某个流行的
network.
社交网络
iOS's solution for
iOS 为在社交网络上
authenticating against a social
使用类似 O-Off 的技术
network using a technique like
进行认证提供的解决方案
o-Off is Safari View Controller.
Safari 视图控制器
And the reason for that is that
这样做的原因是
Safari View controller has
Safari 视图控制器具备
Safari's AutoFill feature, which
Safari 的自动填充功能
makes it really easy to get
这让登录变得
logged in.
很容易
And also, Safari View Controller
与此同时 Safari 视图控制器
is sandboxed away from the third
还是隔绝第三方 App 的沙箱技术
party app, which gives the
这会给被认证的服务
service that's being
一种保障
authenticated to a sort of
保证了
guarantee about the security of
密码的
the passwords.
安全
In iOS 11 Safari View Controller
在 iOS 11里面  Safari 视图控制器
has been revamped.
得到了更新
It has a new look that you can
具有了新的外观
customize to make it feel more
你可以定制外观 让它
like part of your application.
看上去更像你 App 的一部分
So here you're seeing a demo app
大家看到这个演示用 App
presenting a Safari View
它上面的 Safari 视图
Controller tinted blue and
控制器的颜色是
white.
蓝白相间的
It doesn't look very much like
它看上去不像
Safari.
Safari 的一部分
It looks like the app itself.
而是像这个 App 本身
And what this app has also done
同时 这个 App 还
is change the top left corner
把Safari 视图控制器
button of the Safari View
左上角的按键
Controller to say Cancel instead
改成了“Cancel” 而不是原来的
of Done.
“Done”
Because when Safari View
因为在 Safari 视图控制器
Controller is being used for
被用于认证时
authentication, dismissing the
关闭 Safari 视图
Safari View Controller is
控制器就
cancelling the action of logging
意味着取消
in.
登录
It's not actually successfully
而不是代表成功地
finishing anything.
完成了某件事
So Done doesn't make sense.
所以用“Done”就没有意义了
To learn about even more
要了解更多关于
customizations to Safari View
Safari 视图控制器
Controller, and how to implement
自定义的问题 以及如何执行
what I just showed you, you
我刚才演示的这些行为
should definitely check out the
请大家务必去参加
session tomorrow at 10 a.m.
明天上午 10 点的会议
What's New in Safari View
“What’s New in Safari View Controller
Controller.
（Safari 视图控制器新内容）”
And if you want to learn more
如果你想了解
information about implementing
如何使用 Safari 视图控制器
an o-OFF flow yourself using
执行一个 O-OFF 流程
Safari View Controller, you can
你可以回顾
go back to the 2015 session
2015 年的会议
Introducing Safari View
“Introducing Safari View Controller
Controller.
（Safari 视图控制器简介）”
You might not even be
你甚至可能不用
implementing a Safari View
亲自去执行 Safari 视图
Controller yourself to do o-Off,
控制器来实现 O-Off
it might actually come for free
实际上它可能作为
as part of an SDK you're using
你为了认证所使用的 SDK
for authentication.
的一部分免费实现
So that's worth knowing.
这确实值得一提
All right.
好了
Let's talk about everything that
咱们总结一下今天
we've covered so far.
讲解的内容
Friction when logging in can
登录时带来的麻烦
lead users to abandoning your
可能会让用户卸载
app.
你的 App
And we don't want that.
我们不希望这类事情发生
Your apps are awesome.
你的 App 特别棒
We want users to use them.
我们希望用户使用它们
But fortunately in iOS 11,
幸好在 iOS 11 里
Password AutoFill is there to
密码自动填充能够
help.
派上用场
And Password AutoFill uses
密码自动填充在很多 App 里
heuristics to work automatically
使用启发式算法
in many of your apps without you
自动工作
having to make any changes.
你不用做任何改变
But to give your users the best
但为了给用户
experience, and to guarantee
最佳体验 并保证
that it works now and in the
现在和未来都会
future, you can take a few
有效 你还需要采取简单的
simple steps.
几步措施
The first is to install one of
首先在你的手机中
the betas on your phone and run
安装测试版 iOS 11
your app and see what your
并运行你的 App
starting place is.
看看当前的状态
From there, you can adopt the
然后你可以采用
username and password text
用户名与密码文本
content types.
内容类型
That will guarantee that even if
那会保证 即便
iOS or your view hierarchy
iOS 或者你的视图分层
changes a few years from now
在未来几年发生了变化
Password AutoFill will still be
密码自动填充还是会有效
So if you take three minutes to
现在花 3 分钟做这件事
do this now, you might save
你就可能
yourself a bug a few years from
在几年后避免了一个 Bug 出现的
now.
可能性
And then finally, by adopting
最后 通过使用
the webcredentials Associated
网络认证关联
Domain service you can set up a
域名服务 你可以在你的 App
tight two-way link between your
和你的网站之间设置一个
app and your website.
紧密的双向链接
And that will enable iOS to
那会让 iOS 为
offer the exact right
用户提供他们需要的
credentials that your users are
正确的身份信息
looking for, that they've
他们已经把这个信息
already saved in Safari and
存储在 Safari 和
iCloud Keychain directly on the
iCloud 钥匙串里 现在这些信息就能
keyboard in your apps.
直接出现在你 App 的键盘上了
And if you run into any issues
如果你在今年夏天
adopting Password AutoFill this
使用密码自动填充的时候出现了
summer, and you can't fix them
任何问题 你可以用
by taking one of the steps that
我刚才提过的方法
I just outlined, please send us
解决它们 并给我们发来
feedback.
反馈
Please file bugs.
请记录 Bug
We need your help to make sure
我们需要你们的帮助 以确保
that users are getting the best
用户在你们的 App 里
experience in your app and in
在现场所有人的 App 里
the apps of everyone in this
能得到最佳
room.
体验
Your feedback really helps us
你们的反馈会对我们的工作
prioritize our work.
大有帮助
For more information about
想了解关于
Password AutoFill, you can check
密码自动填充的更多信息
out this web page on the
请参阅开发人员网站上的
Developer website.
这个网页
And we have some awesome related
今年我们还有几场相关会议
sessions this year.
都非常好
I already talked about the
我刚才已经说过有
Safari View Controller sessions.
Safari 视图控制器演讲
But on Friday morning there is a
周五早晨还有一场
session that's about making the
讲的是让你 App 内的
keyboard entry experience in
键盘输入体验
your app magical.
变得更棒
I encourage you to check it out.
建议大家都去看
All right.
好了
Thank you so much everybody.
谢谢大家
I hope you have an amazing WWDC.
祝大家享受你们的 WWDC 旅程
[ Applause ]
[掌声]